Hey everybody, welcome to the section
on 5.8 of your textbook, sorting lists.
And this is kind of ironic because this
is actually a really complicated and very
technical idea in programming.
And this is going to be a
pretty quick content video.
So all we're going to go over
in this content video is the
sort function. So let's go
ahead and jump over into our
code space, sorting lists.
So all you really need to know
is that there is a function
that will sort a list for you.
So let's say we've got a list
1, 2, 5, I don't know, 2, 9,
4, 11, something like that.
What the sort function
does is it just returns
it in, you guessed it,
smallest to greatest order.
So if I said list.sort
and print out my list.
We would expect to see
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 9, and 11.
So the only other thing
that I think that's worth
mentioning with this content
video is that if you're
sorting letters, so let's
say we have, oh, this is fun.
Let's say we have a
variable called today, and
I'll set that equal to, I
think it's Monday today.
and what I want to do is I want
to do today dot sort actually I
lied this won't work on a string
I don't think yeah okay you
guys caught me but if we had for
example a list of the characters
in the string Monday,
we sorted that, you
would expect to see the
letters in alphabetical order.
So that's pretty cool, except
that capital letters are
technically more, they have more
precedent than lowercase letters.
So that's why the M, capital
M, is still at the beginning of
our list. That's about everything
for this content video. So
yeah, sort will sort numbers
from smallest to greatest, and
letters from in alphabetical
order. So, thanks for watching.